Dreyer family. Papers of the Dreyer family, 1778-1928: A Finding Aid
Papers of the Dreyer family 1778-1928
- Series IV. FOURTH GENERATION: CORRESPONDENCE, 1837-1893, n.d. (#6.8-14.3)
  - Subseries A. Children of Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803) and Thaddea Henriette Dreier (née Schacht, b.1806) and their spouses, 1837-1881, n.d. (#6.8-11.11, 13.9)
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his brother Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836), n.d., 10.5.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his sister-in-law Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839), 1865, 10.6.
    - Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) to his children Margaretha (Gretchen) Dreier (b.1868) and Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1872), 1878, n.d., 10.7.
    - To Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) from different persons, 1837-1878, n.d.; includes: report card of 1843, 10.8.
    - Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829) to her father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1846, 1865; re: cure in Bad Pyrmont, 10.9.
    - Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829) to her brother Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828), 1845, 1869; re: her disease and oncoming death, 10.10.
    - Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829) to her sister-in-law and cousin Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1865-1869, n.d.; re: duties of her sister-in-law as housewife; Christmas celebrations; death of children of sister-in-law; her disease; poems, 10.11.
    - To Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829) from different persons, 1851-1870, n.d.; re: her disease, 10.12.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1853-1858; re: education at boarding school "Rauhes Haus" in Hamburg-Horn; life and travels as sailor, 10.13.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1859-1860; re: life and travels as sailor; death of mother, 10.14.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1863, 1865; re: complaints about life as sailor; loss of his ship "Circassian" near Halifax, 10.15.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1866-1867; re: travels as an officer on board of steamship, 10.16.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1868; re: farm labor in Iowa, 10.17.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1869; re: life as farmer in Pleasant Grove, Des Moines County, Iowa; sketch of farm; death of nephew; wedding with Bertha Dreier (née Obermann, b.1846), 10.18.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1870; re: celebration of July 4th; taxes and expenditures; death of sister Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829), 11.1.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1871; re: life as farmer in Iowa; end of Franco-Prussian War (1870-1871), 11.2.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1872; re: life as farmer in Iowa; debts, 11.3.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his parents Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803) and Thaddea Henriette Dreier (née Schacht, b.1806), 1853-1860, n.d.; re: education at boarding school "Rauhes Haus" in Hamburg-Horn; life and travels as sailor, 11.4.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his brother Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828), 1853-1871; re: travel to Iowa, 11.5.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his sister Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829), 1866-1870; re: life as sailor and as farmer in Iowa; disease and oncoming death of sister, 11.6.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his brother Julius Alexander Dreier (b.1838), 1856, 11.7.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to his sister-in-law and cousin Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1875, 11.8.
    - Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to Mrs. Oldenberg, 1853, 11.9.
    - Bertha Dreier (née Obermann, b.1846), wife of Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836) to her father-in-law Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803) and her sister-in-law Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1870-1875; re: life on farm in Iowa, 11.10.
    - Julius Alexander Dreier (b.1838) to his father Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1856, 11.11.
  - Subseries B. Children of Julius Alexander Dreier (b.1805) and his first wife Metta Lucie Wilhelmine Dreier (née Noltenius, b.1800) and his second wife Margaretha (Meta) Catharina Dreier (née Lampe, b.1813), 1860-1869, (#11.12-11.15)
    - Johannes Caspar Heinrich Dreier (b.1833) to his uncle Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1860, 11.12.
    - Cornelius Heinrich Dreier (b.1838) to his cousin Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829), 1862 and 1866, 11.13.
    - Dorothea (Doris) Hermanna Dreier (b.1841) to her cousin Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829), 1863-1869, 11.14.
    - Magdalene Henriette Wilhelmine Dreier (b.1842) to her cousin Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829), 1865-1869, 11.15.
  - Subseries C. Children of August Ferdinand Dreier (b.1808) and his first wife Sophie Friederike Elisabeth (Betty) Dreier (née Focke, b.1808), 1863-1870, n.d. (#11.16-11.17, 12.21)
    - Christine Emma Elisabeth Pferdmenges (née Dreier, b.1842) (?) to her cousin Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1863, 12.21.
    - Johannes Theodor Ernst Dreier (b.1844) to his uncle Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1866-1870, 11.16.
    - Johannes Theodor Ernst Dreier (b.1844) to his cousin Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829), n.d., 11.17.
  - Subseries D. Children of Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) and Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817) and their spouses, 1848-1893, n.d. (#11.18-12.20, 12.22-13.8, 13.10-14.3)
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her grandmother Mrs. Hotzen, 1848-1868, 11.18.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her father Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811), 1866, 11.19.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her mother Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), 1866-1880, n.d.; re: pension (boarding house) business at home in Bad Pyrmont; family life with eleven children; pleurisy of daughter, 11.20.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her uncle Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1870, 11.21.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1853-1859, n.d., 11.22.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1860-1864; re: marriage of sister, 11.23.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1865-1866; re: family life; physical condition and cure in Bad Pyrmont; birth and death of sister's first child, 11.24.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1867-1868; re: children from first marriage of her husband; fear of death after birth; birth of second and third child of sister; reluctance regarding marriage of uncle with a wife with a supposedly bad reputation, 11.25.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1869-1870, n.d.; re: professional future of husband and possible move; death of second child of sister; difficult economic situation of family; remittance of sister; disease of daughter; move to Bad Pyrmont; sketch of new house with husband's pharmacy; Franco-Prussian War (1870-1871), 12.1.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1871-1872; re: Franco-Prussian War (1870-1871); difficult economic situation of family; agony and death of daughter; criticism at hands in pharmacy and servants in household; gifts of sister to support family; criticism of brother and former foster child of parents, 12.2.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1873-1874; re: criticism of former foster child of parents; family life; housework; pension (boarding house) business at home in Bad Pyrmont; schooling of children, 12.3.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1875-1877; re: schooling of children; professional future of husband; state of exhaustion and ninth pregnancy; housework, 12.4.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1878-1879; re: training of children from first marriage of husband, Heinrich Knoch (b.1855) and Hanna(h) Knoch (b.1858); housework; pastors; criticism of brother-in-law Karl Wilhelm Dreier (b.1836); purchase of university pharmacy (Universitaetsapotheke) in Giessen and move of family, 12.5.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1880-1881; re: education and schooling of children; difficult economic situation of pharmacy in Giessen and of family; gifts of sister for family; aging and exhaustion; legal proceedings against former owner of pharmacy; bad condition of house; death of former foster child of parents; criticism of life and economic failure of brother; purchase of house in Krefeld, 12.6.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), n.d., 12.7.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her brother-in-law Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828), 1875-1880, 12.8.
    - Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to her cousin Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829), 1866, 12.9.
    - Friedrich Heinrich Wilhelm Knoch (b.1826), husband of Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to his father-in-law Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811), 1875, 1880, 12.10.
    - Friedrich Heinrich Wilhelm Knoch (b.1826), husband of Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) to his sister-in-law Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1862-1873, n.d., 12.11.
    - Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) to her grandmother Mrs. Hotzen, 1848-1862, n.d., 12.12.
    - Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) to her father Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811), 1881-1882, 12.13.
    - Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) to her mother Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), 1863, 12.14.
    - Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) to her father-in-law Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1864-1871; re: arrival in United States; life in Brooklyn and Staten Island; death of children, 12.15.
    - Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) to her father-in-law Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1871-1872; re: life in Brooklyn; preparation of wild duck and prairie chicken, 12.16.
    - Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) to her husband Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828), 1869-1870, 12.17.
    - Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) to her siblings Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839),; Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) and former foster child of parents Carl Radatz (circulars), 1872-1880; re: everyday life with family in Brooklyn; physical condition of Carl Radatz, 12.18.
    - Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) to her sister-in-law and cousin Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829), 1864-1870, n.d.; re: family life in Brooklyn; death of children; disease and physical condition of sister-in-law and cousin, 12.19.
    - Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) to her daughter Margaretha (Gretchen) Dreier Robins (née Dreier, b.1868), 1872, 12.20.
    - To Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) from members of Hotzen family, 1857-1863, 12.22.
    - To Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) from members of Hotzen family, 1864-1881, n.d.; re: marriage with her cousin Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and emigration to United States, 13.1.
    - To Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) from different persons, 1853-1860, 13.2.
    - To Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) from different persons, 1861-1863, 13.3.
    - To Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) from different persons, 1864; re: marriage with her cousin Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and emigration to United States, 13.4.
    - To Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) from different persons, 1865-1876; re: description of a domestic (?) of sickness, agony and death of her father-in-law Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803); history of illness and autopsy of her daughter Margaretha Henriette Dreier (b.1865), 13.5.
    - To Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) from different persons, 1871-1881, n.d., some in English, 13.6.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his grandmother Mrs. Hotzen, 1850-1861, n.d., 13.7.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his father Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811), 1865-1881; re: financial investment of father; work at Naylor Co. in New York, 13.8.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his mother Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), 1854-1858, n.d.; re: education at home of uncle and aunt in Hanover, 13.10.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his mother Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), 1863-1889; re: work at Naylor Co. and social life (e.g. at German Club) in New York, 13.11.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his mother Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), 1890-1893, n.d.; re: work at Naylor Co. and social life (e.g. at German Club) in New York; purchase of an ore mine in the Adirondack mountains; work as agent for a life insurance company, 13.12.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his parents Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) and Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), 1867-1868; re: bonds of parents; work at Naylor Co. in New York; trips to surrounding areas and to Niagara Falls; religious and social life in New York, 13.13.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his parents Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) and Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), 1869-1881, n.d.; re: work at Naylor Co. in New York; foundation of his own company Stietz Dreier (relief glass letters and numbers); financial investment of father; bonds of parents; Franco-Prussian War (1870-1871), 13.14.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his uncle Gustav Theodor Dreier (b.1803), 1865-1872, 13.15.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to an aunt, 1865; re: passage on board of ship to New York, 13.21.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1855-1864; re: life at uncle's and aunt's home in Bremen, 13.16.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1865-1872; re: life at uncle's and aunt's home in Bremen; work as clerk, 13.17.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1873-1881, one letter in English; re: information about boarding house in Hanover; journey to Italy and Switzerland; social life in New York, 13.18.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his brother-in-law Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828), 1865-1881; re: professional situation, 13.19.
    - Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) to his niece Margaretha (Gretchen) Dreier Robins (née Dreier, b.1868), 1876, 13.20.
    - To Johann Caspar Ludwig Dreier (b.1843) from Naylor Co., 1891; re: Dreier's abandonment of Naylor Co., 13.22.
    - Carl Radatz, former foster child of Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) and his wife Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), to his "grandmother" Mrs. Hotzen, 1859, n.d., 14.1.
    - Carl Radatz, former foster child of Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) and his wife Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), to his foster parents or his foster mother, 1865-1878; re: schooling in Hanover; journey along river Neckar; studies at technical school in Stuttgart; his lung disease (presumably tuberculosis) and stay in Montreux, 14.2.
    - Carl Radatz, former foster child of Heinrich Eduard Dreier (b.1811) and his wife Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), to Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1862-1875, n.d.; re: marrige of Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) with Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828); situation of his three biological brothers, of former foster mother and of Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839); his lung disease (presumably tuberculosis) and stays in France, Switzerland, and Italy, 14.3.
- Series V. FIFTH GENERATION: CORRESPONDENCE, 1872-1917, n.d. (#14.4-14.17)
  Series V, FIFTH GENERATION: CORRESPONDENCE, 1872-1917, n.d., (#14.4-14.17), contains correspondence of the grandchildren of the four sons of Johann Caspar Dreier (formerly Dreyer, b.1758) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Uhthoff, b.1774) and their spouses.
  - Hanna(h) Knoch (b.1858), daughter of Friedrich Heinrich Wilhelm Knoch (b.1826) and Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839) from Knoch's first marriage, to her aunt Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840) and her cousin Margaretha (Gretchen) Dreier Robins (née Dreier, b.1868), 1875-1876, 14.4.
  - Alma Knoch (b.1862), daughter of Friedrich Heinrich Wilhelm Knoch (b.1826) and Margaretha (Meta) Knoch (neé Dreier, b.1839), to her aunt Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), n.d., 14.5.
  - Margaretha (Gretchen) Dreier Robins (née Dreier, b.1868), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), to her parents, 1881, n.d., includes stitch sample cards, 14.6.
  - To Margaretha (Gretchen) Dreier Robins (née Dreier, b.1868), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), from Ellen Brackett, 1882-1915, n.d., in English, 14.7.
  - To Margaretha (Gretchen) Dreier Robins (née Dreier, b.1868), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), from Mary A. Brackett, 1881-1891, n.d., in English, 14.8.
  - To Margaretha (Gretchen) Dreier Robins (née Dreier, b.1868), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), from different persons, 1872-1891, n.d., mainly in English, 14.9.
  - Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (b.1870), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), to her parents, 1881, n.d., 14.10.
  - To Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (b.1870), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), from different persons, 1907-1912, mainly in English, 14.11.
  - To Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (b.1870), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), from different persons, 1913-1917, mainly in English, 14.12.
  - To Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (b.1870), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), from different persons, n.d., in English, 14.13.
  - Heinrich (Henry) Eduard Dreier (b.1872), son of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), to his parents, 1881, n.d, 14.14.
  - To Heinrich (Henry) Eduard Dreier (b.1872), son of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), from different persons, 1881, n.d., 14.17.
  - Marie (Mary) Elisabeth Dreier (b.1875), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), to her parents, n.d, 14.15.
  - Katherine Sophie Dreier (b.1877), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), to her mother, her sister Margaretha (Gretchen) Dreier Robins (née Dreier, b.1868) and her sister Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (b.1870), 1889, n.d., two letters in English, 14.16.
- Series VI. UNIDENTIFIABLE LETTERS AND OTHER PAPERS, 1778-1928, n.d. (#14.18-15.4)
  Series VI, UNIDENTIFIABLE LETTERS AND OTHER PAPERS, 1778-1928, n.d., (#14.18-15.4), contains unidentifiable letters and private papers of different members of the Dreier family, mostly bills, notebooks and handwritten poems (mostly religious or on the occasion of family celebrations).
  - Unidentifiable letters, 1778-1872, n.d., 14.18.
  - Bills regarding dowry of Margaretha (Meta) Thibetha Dreier (née Hotzen, b.1817), 1838, 14.19.
  - Printed family tree of Dreier family (photocopy), 1928, 14.20.
  - Poems (mostly religious or on occasion of family celebrations), 1821-1866, n.d., 14.21.
  - Poems (mostly religious or on occasion of family celebrations), 1856-1861, n.d., 14.22.
  - Various papers, 1827-1872, n.d., including entry of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) into Dreier company; programs of private concerts; religious writings; will of Dorothea Henriette Christine Dreier (b.1829); drawing of farm buildings; notebooks with short travelogs, 15.1.
  - Various papers, probably of Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Uhthoff, b.1774), 1800-1831, n.d., including notebooks with religious writings; printed hymn sheets; paper cut with saints, 15.2.
  - Papers of Margaretha (Gretchen) Dreier Robins (née Dreier, b.1868), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1875-1903, n.d., including report card of German School (Deutsche Schule) in Brooklyn, 15.3.
  - Papers of Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (b.1870), daughter of Johann Caspar Theodor Dreier (b.1828) and Dorothea Adelheid Dreier (née Dreier, b.1840), 1907-1922, n.d., including bills, calling cards, State Platform of National Progressive Party of State of New York, 15.4.
Additional catalog entries
The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic databases. THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.
Authors
Dreier, Katherine Sophie, 1877-1952
Dreier, Mary E. (Mary Elisabeth), 1875-1963
Subjects
Antenuptial contracts--Germany--Prussia
Childbirth
Children--Conduct of life
Children--Death
Children--Health and hygiene
Clergy--Germany--Prussia
Domestics--Germany--Prussia
Families of clergy--Germany--Prussia
Farm life--Iowa
Franco Prussian War, 1870-1871
Germans--United States
Health resorts--Europe
Iowa--Rural conditions
Love-letters
Marriage--Germany--Prussia
Marriage--United States
Mothers and daughters
Orphans--Germany--Prussia
Parent and child
Poems
Pregnancy
Prussia (Germany)--Politics and government--1848-1866
Prussia (Germany)--Politics and government--1870-1947
Prussia (Germany)--Religious life and customs
Prussia (Germany)--Social life and customs--19th century
Unites States--Emigration and immigration
Unites States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Personal narratives
Voyages and travels
Women--Religious life--Germany--Prussia